[
  {
    "question": "Where are found most of the volcanoes?",
    "optionOne": "Close to the tectonic plates boundaries.",
    "optionTwo": "Where the ground is soft.",
    "optionThree": "On the continental crust .",
    "correctAnswer": "Close to the tectonic plates boundaries."
  },
  {
    "question": "From which layer of the earth magma comes from?",
    "optionOne": "The inner core.",
    "optionTwo": "The mantle.",
    "optionThree": "The Crust.",
    "correctAnswer": "The mantle."
  },
  {
    "question": "What composes the earth's crust?",
    "optionOne": "The continental and oceanic crust.",
    "optionTwo": "The upper and lower mantle.",
    "optionThree": "The oceans and continents.",
    "correctAnswer": "The continental and oceanic crust."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are tectonic plates?",
    "optionOne": "Seismic zones.",
    "optionTwo": "Continents.",
    "optionThree": "Sections of rocks constantly moving.",
    "correctAnswer": "Sections of rocks constantly moving."
  },
  {
    "question": "Where is magma collected?",
    "optionOne": "In a magma room.",
    "optionTwo": "In a magma box.",
    "optionThree": "In a magma chamber.",
    "correctAnswer": "In a magma chamber."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the volcano types is the result of low viscosity lava?",
    "optionOne": "Shield volcano.",
    "optionTwo": "Dome volcano.",
    "optionThree": "Caldera volcano.",
    "correctAnswer": "Shield volcano."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the other name for composite volcano?",
    "optionOne": "Compovolcano.",
    "optionTwo": "Stratovolcano.",
    "optionThree": "Bulkovolcano.",
    "correctAnswer": "Stratovolcano."
  },
  {
    "question": "What characterized explosive eruption?",
    "optionOne": "Outpouring of lava with low viscosity and gas.",
    "optionTwo": "Volcano's hight and location.",
    "optionThree": "Violent gas, ahes and rocks emission.",
    "correctAnswer": "Violent gas, ahes and rocks emission."
  },
  {
    "question": "What characterized effusive eruption?",
    "optionOne": "Outpouring of lava with low viscosity and gas.",
    "optionTwo": "Violent gas, ahes and rocks emission.",
    "optionThree": "Number of volcanic eruptions in the past 10 years.",
    "correctAnswer": "Outpouring of lava with low viscosity and gas."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following isn't a type of volcanic erruption?",
    "optionOne": "Vulcanian.",
    "optionTwo": "Latin.",
    "optionThree": "Pelean.",
    "correctAnswer": "Latin."
  },
  {
    "question": "Where are found 90% of the active vocanoes?",
    "optionOne": "In the Atlantic Ring of Fire.",
    "optionTwo": "In the Arctic Ring of Fire.",
    "optionThree": "In the Pacific Ring of Fire.",
    "correctAnswer": "In the Pacific Ring of Fire."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the longest mountain range on earth?",
    "optionOne": "The mid-ocean ridge.",
    "optionTwo": "The himalayas.",
    "optionThree": "The mariana trench.",
    "correctAnswer": "The mid-ocean ridge."
  },
  {
    "question": "What act as giant moving belt for the tectonic plates?",
    "optionOne": "The inner core.",
    "optionTwo": "The astenosphere.",
    "optionThree": "The oceanic crust.",
    "correctAnswer": "The astenosphere."
  },
  {
    "question": "A fast moving mudflow made of volcanic ash and water is the definition of?",
    "optionOne": "Brown lava.",
    "optionTwo": "Volcanic mud.",
    "optionThree": "Lahar.",
    "correctAnswer": "Lahar."
  },
  {
    "question": "How much of the earth land surface rainforests cover?",
    "optionOne": "4%.",
    "optionTwo": "12%.",
    "optionThree": "21%.",
    "correctAnswer": "12%."
  },
  {
    "question": "What does equable mean?",
    "optionOne": "With the same amount.",
    "optionTwo": "With not much variation.",
    "optionThree": "Within the equator.",
    "correctAnswer": "With not much variation."
  },
  {
    "question": "How many layers structure the the jungle?",
    "optionOne": "4.",
    "optionTwo": "6.",
    "optionThree": "8.",
    "correctAnswer": "4."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why the vegetation of the understory layer develops large leaves?",
    "optionOne": "To catch as much water as possible.",
    "optionTwo": "To host a specific parasite.",
    "optionThree": "To catch the remaining sunlight.",
    "correctAnswer": "To catch the remaining sunlight."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is buttress roots?",
    "optionOne": "An animal only living in tree's roots.",
    "optionTwo": "Shallow and widespread roots structure.",
    "optionThree": "A name given to very soft roots.",
    "correctAnswer": "Shallow and widespread roots structure."
  },
  {
    "question": "What characterize the Canopy?",
    "optionOne": "Dense vegetation with a huge network of branches and leaves.",
    "optionTwo": "Light vegetation with definite and seperated zones.",
    "optionThree": "Dark and humide where vegetation has difficulty to grow.",
    "correctAnswer": "Dense vegetation with a huge network of branches and leaves."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why trees develop buttress roots?",
    "optionOne": "To prevent other trees to grow.",
    "optionTwo": "To catch as much sunlight as possible.",
    "optionThree": "Because the humus layer is very thin.",
    "correctAnswer": "Because the humus layer is very thin."
  },
  {
    "question": "How hight can reach the Emergent layer?",
    "optionOne": "60 meters.",
    "optionTwo": "100 meters.",
    "optionThree": "120 meters.",
    "correctAnswer": "60 meters."
  },
  {
    "question": "What part of the animals population live in the canopy?",
    "optionOne": "About 21%.",
    "optionTwo": "About 50%.",
    "optionThree": "About 90%.",
    "correctAnswer": "About 50%."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is biology?",
    "optionOne": "The science of organism living in pairs.",
    "optionTwo": "The science of life and living organisms.",
    "optionThree": "The person that study the Earth.",
    "correctAnswer": "The science of life and living organisms."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which is the largest rainforest?",
    "optionOne": "The Amazon.",
    "optionTwo": "The Daintree.",
    "optionThree": "The Congo.",
    "correctAnswer": "The Amazon."
  },
  {
    "question": "About 25% of what comes from the Jungle?",
    "optionOne": "Medicines.",
    "optionTwo": "Wood.",
    "optionThree": "Water.",
    "correctAnswer": "Medicines."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is humus?",
    "optionOne": "The decay of the forest elements.",
    "optionTwo": "A species of frog.",
    "optionThree": "The name a flower that only Grows in the jungle.",
    "correctAnswer": "The decay of the forest elements."
  },
  {
    "question": "Where is situated the Amazon?",
    "optionOne": "South Africa.",
    "optionTwo": "South America.",
    "optionThree": "Australia.",
    "correctAnswer": "South America."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is latest ocean created?",
    "optionOne": "The Arctic.",
    "optionTwo": "The Antarctic.",
    "optionThree": "The Indian.",
    "correctAnswer": "The Arctic."
  },
  {
    "question": "Where is the salt of the ocean mainly from?",
    "optionOne": "Melting ice caps.",
    "optionTwo": "Erosion of rocks on land.",
    "optionThree": "Rain.",
    "correctAnswer": "Erosion of rocks on land."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the color of the ocean?",
    "optionOne": "Transparent.",
    "optionTwo": "It depends on the sky.",
    "optionThree": "Blue-green.",
    "correctAnswer": "Blue-green."
  },
  {
    "question": "How many tides occur each day?",
    "optionOne": "2.",
    "optionTwo": "3.",
    "optionThree": "4.",
    "correctAnswer": "2."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a flood tide?",
    "optionOne": "When the tide is going towards the low tide.",
    "optionTwo": "When the level of the water is still.",
    "optionThree": "When the tide is going towards the hight tide.",
    "correctAnswer": "When the tide is going towards the hight tide."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is an ocean current?",
    "optionOne": "The conductivity of the water.",
    "optionTwo": "A continuous movement of water.",
    "optionThree": "A still body of water.",
    "correctAnswer": "A continuous movement of water."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are created by wind, water temperature, salinity and tides?",
    "optionOne": "Ocean's currents.",
    "optionTwo": "Ocean's waves.",
    "optionThree": "Ocean's names.",
    "correctAnswer": "Ocean currents."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why is the ocean playing an important role in the climate regulation?",
    "optionOne": "Because It is cold.",
    "optionTwo": "Because it transports heat from the equator to the poles.",
    "optionThree": "Because it is hugely used for transportation.",
    "correctAnswer": "Because it transports heat from the equator to the poles."
  },
  {
    "question": "How much of the total water on earth is in the ocean?",
    "optionOne": "About 50%.",
    "optionTwo": "About 70%.",
    "optionThree": "About 90%.",
    "correctAnswer": "About 90%."
  },
  {
    "question": "How much of the esrth surface is covered by the Pacific Ocean?",
    "optionOne": "30%.",
    "optionTwo": "40%.",
    "optionThree": "50%.",
    "correctAnswer": "30%."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is sublimation?",
    "optionOne": "Water changing state from liquid to vapor.",
    "optionTwo": "Water changing state from solid to liquid.",
    "optionThree": "Water changing state from solid to vapor.",
    "correctAnswer": "Water changing state from solid to vapor."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is water vapor?",
    "optionOne": "A gas invisible to the eye.",
    "optionTwo": "A cloud.",
    "optionThree": "Liquid water.",
    "correctAnswer": "A gas invisible to the eye."
  },
  {
    "question": "If all the salt of the ocean would be spread on the earth land surface, how hight would it go?",
    "optionOne": "50 meters.",
    "optionTwo": "150 meters.",
    "optionThree": "300 meters.",
    "correctAnswer": "150 meters."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the current that transport more water than all the rivers on earth combined?",
    "optionOne": "The North Pacific Drift.",
    "optionTwo": "Equatorial Countercurrent.",
    "optionThree": "The Gulf Stream.",
    "correctAnswer": "The Gulf Stream."
  }
]